<resources>
    <string name="app_name">CUSD</string>

    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close navigation drawer</string>
    <string name="introduction_blurb">In order to support the success of all Chandler Unified School
        District (CUSD) students, the departments of Equity &amp; Inclusion and Counseling &amp; Social Services
        will host the inaugural summer educational equity symposium - Breaking Barriers for Excellence.
        This two-day event seeks to build the capacity of faculty and staff. Members of the CUSD community
        will explore:
\n\n Culturally relevant pedagogy
\n Suicide awareness and prevention
\n Adverse Childhood Experiences (ACEs)
\n Implicit and unconscious bias
\n Collaboration between schools and communities, and
\n A host of socio-emotional-learning and instructional strategies.
\n\n The professional development will allow faculty and staff to be immersed in learning with the goal
of transforming CUSD in meeting our Journey 2025 strategic plan. The two-day symposium invites thought
leaders (national and local) and CUSD faculty to create a space for \"courageous conversations\". The space
will allow educators to build a deeper understanding of our diverse learning community, explore best practices
in meeting the varied learning needs of our students, and fulfill the promise to our parents.</string>
    <string name="day1schedule"><b>7:30 AM</b>
    \n Welcome
    \n Room: Auditorium
        \n \n <b>8:00 AM</b>
        \n Keynote: Dr. Angelina Castagno - The Price of Nice: How Niceness Reinforces Educational Inequity
        \n Room: Auditorium
        \n \n <b>9:15 AM</b>
        \n CUSD Leadership Track - Unpacking the Keynote with Dr. Castagno
        \n Room: Cafeteria
        \n \n <b>9:15 AM</b>
        \n Breakout Session 1
        \n Room: Various
        \n \n <b>10:30 AM</b>
        \n Breakout Session 2
        \n Room: Various
        \n \n <b>11:30</b>
        \n Lunch
        \n Room: Cafeteria
        \n \n <b>12:30 PM</b>
        \n Keynote: Marcia Stanton - Understanding ACEs and Their Impact on Learning, Development and Behavior in School
        \n Room: Auditorium
        \n \n <b>1:45 PM</b>
        \n Teacher Equity Leadership Track - Unpacking the Keynote with Dr. Castagno
        \n Room: Cafeteria
        \n \n <b>1:45 PM</b>
        \n Breakout Session 3
        \n Room: Various
        \n \n <b>3:00 PM</b>
        \n TED Talk Parent Panel - Stories Are Important: Let Me Tell You About My Child/Children
        \n Room: Auditorium
    </string>
    <string name="day1"><b>Day 1</b></string>
    <string name="day2"><b>Day 2</b></string>
    <string name="day2schedule"><b>7:30 AM</b>
    \n Welcome
    \n Room: Auditorium
    \n \n <b>8:00 AM</b>
    \n Keynote: Dr. Tyrone Howard - Educating and Supporting Boys and Young Men of Color
    \n Room: Auditorium
    \n \n <b>9:15 AM</b>
    \n CUSD Leadership Track - Unpacking the Keynote with Dr. Howard
    \n Room: Cafeteria
    \n \n <b>9:15 AM</b>
    \n Breakout Session 1
    \n Room: Various
    \n \n <b>10:30 AM</b>
    \n Breakout Session 2
    \n Room: Various
        \n \n <b>11:30 AM</b>
        \n Lunch
        \n Cafeteria
        \n \n <b>12:30 PM</b>
        \n Keynote: Dr. William De La Cruz - Deconstructing our Blindspots - Examining the Role of Bias (Unconscious and Conscious) and its Implications for Educators
        \n Room: Auditorium
        \n \n <b>1:45 PM</b>
        \n CUSD Leadership Track - Unpacking the Keynote with Dr. De La Cruz
        \n Room: Cafeteria
        \n \n <b>1:45 PM</b>
        \n Breakout Session 3
        \n Room: Various
        \n \n <b>3:00 PM</b>
        \n Student Voice Panel - Can we say something? We are really the experts about school and learning
        \n Room: Auditorium
    </string>
    <string name="keynotes"><b>Keynote Speakers</b></string>
    <string name="sessiondescr"><b>Session Descriptions</b></string>
    <string name="castagnoname">Dr. Angelina Castagno</string>
    <string name="castagnodescr"><b>The Price of Nice: How Niceness Perpetuates Educational Inequity</b>
    \n \n Despite their good intentions and the general Niceness among educators, most schools in the United States contribute to inequity every day.
        How does this happen? And what might be done about this paradox? The opening keynote will address these questions so that we can begin to examine our own
        role in patterned educational inequities, and specifically, how our Niceness may be getting in the way of our efforts to advance equity in our district.</string>
    <string name="stantonname">Maria Stanton MSW</string>
    <string name="stantondescr"><b>Understanding ACEs and Their Impact on Learning, Development and Behavior in School</b>
    \n \n In Arizona and across the US, educators are working to understand Adverse Childhood Experiences (ACEs) and their impact on learning and behavior.
        This presentation will include a brief overview of the groundbreaking ACEs Study and share ACE incidence data for Arizona children and youth: what the data
        tells us, why schools should care, and what we can do about it.</string>
    <string name="howardname">Tyrone C. Howard, Ph.D.</string>
    <string name="howarddescr"><b>Educating and Supporting Boys and Young Men of Color</b>
    \n \n This keynote examines the educational state of affairs for males of color in schools today, and offers recommendations, strategies, and approaches that
        practitioners and school leaders can take to assist them academically, socially, and emotionally.</string>
    <string name="cruzname">Dr.  William de la Cruz</string>
    <string name="cruzdescr"><b>Deconstructing our Blindspots - Examining the Role of Bias (Unconscious and Conscious) and its Implications
        for Educators</b>
        \n \n In the past 20 years, educational researchers have examined bias, (conscious and unconscious) and its role in shaping perceptions,
        engagement and expectations of students. When unexamined, bias can have implications far beyond the classroom. Thus, recognizing our bias through
        self-awareness is critical for teaching a diverse student body. This keynote will address bias and its repercussion in K-12 settings.</string>
    <string name="sessiondescrdisclaimer">*Each separate session is available for all three Breakout Sessions on the day they are scheduled.</string>
    <string name="sessiondescr5"><b>Children\'s Play: Examining the Impact of Educators\' Conscious and Unconscious Biases on the Social,
    Emotional, and Cognitive Development of Children of African Descent</b>
    \n Latisha Barret
    \n \n <b>Cultivating Equitable Classrooms for Students in Special Education</b>
    \n Michelle Capriotti
    \n \n <b>Say This, Not That</b>
    \n Carla Rivera-Cruz
    \n \n <b>Providing Access - Relationships, Engagement, and Rigor for English Learners</b>
    \n Katherine English
    \n \n <b>Culturally Responsive Practices: Closing the Achievement and Discipline Gap</b>
    \n Yadira Flores
    \n \n <b>Creating Safe Spaces (How to Be an Ally to LGBTQ Youth)</b>
    \n GLSEN
    \n \n <b>Suicide Awareness and Prevention</b>
    \n Paula McCall
    \n \n <b>It Takes a Village!</b>
    \n Dr. Jeff McGee
    \n \n <b>Identifying, Understanding, and Treating Eating Disorders Among Adolescents</b>
    \n Stephanie Paige
    \n \n <b>Be a Warmer Demander: Utilizing Relationship, Relevance, Realness and Rigor</b>
    \n Johnna Pascador
    \n \n <b>Money to Memphis</b>
    \n John Prothro
    \n \n <b>Inclusiveness with LGBTQ+ Students</b>
    \n Kinsey Welsh
    \n \n <b>Cultural Humidity | Equity for Native American Students</b>
    \n Rowdy Duncan </string>
    <string name="sessiondescr6"><b>Reel Indian? Examining the effects of Indigenous Media Representation and its Implication for K-12 Education</b>
    \n Mina Bhagdev
    \n \n <b>The Wellness in You!</b>
    \n Crystal Blackwell
    \n \n <b>Trauma Informed Practices in Education</b>
    \n Carolyn Contreras
    \n \n <b>Boxing in Our Future with Labels</b>
    \n Jasmine Davis
    \n \n <b>Building LGBTQ-Inclusive Elementary Schools: Ready, Set, Respect!</b>
    \n GLSEN
    \n \n <b>The Classroom Teacher\'s Impact on a Student\'s Life Story</b>
    \n Leslie Hicks
    \n \n <b>Non-Suicidal Self-Injury: Understanding and Response</b>
    \n Paula McCall
    \n \n <b>Closing the Achievement Gap: Understanding Classroom Life Through Exploratory Practice</b>
    \n Melanie Mello
    \n \n <b>Not Just About Budgeting: How Participatory Democracy Deepens Civic Engagement and Strengthens School Communities</b>
    \n Sarah Sacco
    \n \n <b>A Dream Deferred</b>
    \n Russell Tribby
    \n \n <b>Building Educators Cultural Capacity about Native American History and Students in Arizona</b>
    \n Leticia Velarde
    \n \n <b>Trauma Informed Educators</b>
    \n Lee Underwood
    \n \n <b>Recruitment and Retention of Non-Traditional (Gender) CTE Students</b>
    \n Tim Wernette</string>
    <string name="junefifth"><b>June 5th</b></string>
    <string name="junesixth"><b>June 6th</b></string>
    <string name="breakoutsessions">Breakout Session Schedules
    \n 9:15 AM - 10:15 AM
    \n 10:30 AM - 11:30 AM
    \n 1:45 PM - 2:45 PM</string>
    <string name="linktosite">Click to see more about these speakers</string>
    <string name="feedblurb"><b>Feedback on your experience here at the symposium is appreciated!</b></string>
    <string name="survey1">Feedback for the symposium on June 5th</string>
    <string name="survey2">Feedback for the symposium on June 6th</string>
    <string name="survey3">Feedback for the overall experience of June 5th</string>
    <string name="survey4">Feedback for the overall experience of June 6th</string>
    <string name="defofterms"><b>The isms: </b>The “isms” are usually based on prejudiced stereotyping that result in discrimination
        which leads to marginalization and are damaging to human health and well-being. Some of the more common “isms” are:
    \n \n  -  <b>Ageism: </b>Linked to age. This “ism” is a widespread and insidious practice. Ageism poses an everyday challenge for
        many people who may be overlooked for employment, restricted from social services, and be stereotyped in the media.
        Ageism marginalizes and excludes people from their communities. The most socially “normalized” and least countered “isms”.
        (Adapted from the World Health Organization website).
    \n \n  -  <b>Heterosexism: </b>The denial, denigration, and stigmatization of any non-heterosexual form of behavior, identity,
        relationship, or community. The term heterosexism was coined to highlight the parallels of this “ism” between antigay
        sentiment, racism, antisemitism, and sexism (UC Davis).
    \n \n  -  <b>Racism: </b>The pre-conceived erroneous beliefs that everyone in a race has the same characteristics, abilities,
        or qualities. These perceptions tend to be linked to group stereotypes and distinguish the race as being inferior
        (Hoyt, 2012).
    \n \n  -  <b>Sexism: </b>Linked to gender. This “ism” is also widespread and is deemed more acceptable than racism (UNICEF).
        Like the other “isms", sexism can have a devastating impact on human lifestyle, health and well-being creating issues
        that range from pay differentials and poor body image, to eating disorders.
    \n \n <b>All of these "isms" are strongly linked to prejudice, power, oppression, and marginalization which are defined below:</b>
    \n \n <b>Prejudice: </b>A preconceived opinion which shows bias and partiality without being based on reason or actual experience
        (Hoyt, 2012). Prejudice has three key features as described on the UC Davis website:
    \n \n - It is an attitude (i.e., an evaluation or judgement)
    \n \n - It is directed at a social group and its members
    \n \n - It is negative, involving hostility or dislike
    \n \n <b>Power: </b>The ability to exert force on or over a person, a thing, or to hold influence within a system (Hoyt, 2012).
    \n \n <b>Oppression: </b>The use of one\’s power or authority in an unjust, onerous, or cruel way (Hoyt, 2012).
    \n \n <b>Culture: </b>Incorporates the shared patterns of understanding, socialization, thought processes, interactions and
        behaviors cultivating in a unique group identity. Culture involves the food, religion, clothes, language, music, attitudes,
        customs, and many more daily occurrences that cultivate and nurture the group identity (LiveScience website).
    \n \n - <b>Cultural Competence: </b>Having cultural competence means recognizing and understanding the importance of cultural and
        social influences on people\’s beliefs and behaviors; considering how the beliefs and behaviors interact at multiple levels
        of the education system (example classroom, school, district); and devising interventions that take these factors into account
        to, ensure quality education for a diverse student population (Betancourt, Green, Carrillo, &amp; Owusu Ananeh-Firempong, 2016).
    \n \n - <b>Cultural Responsive Teaching: </b>Culturally responsive teaching (CRT) is central to meeting student learning needs. CRT
        allows the teacher to effectively communicate AND information. This pedagogy provides equitable educational access for all student
        by recognizing and celebrating individuals and their cultures. Culturally responsive teachers hold a positive outlook on students
        and their families, communicate high expectations for all students, includes student-centered, culturally mediated instruction where
        the teacher is the facilitator. Additionally, the curriculum is reshaped to provide learning experiences within the context of a
        variety of cultures (Brown University).
    \n \n - <b>Cultural Sensitivity: </b>A skill set that allows individuals to learn about and understand those that are different from them.
        This understanding improves the ability of culturally sensitive individuals to meet the needs of the diverse community they serve
        (Penn State University).
    \n \n <b>Diversity: </b>Cultural diversity appreciates each the differences of each individual. There are many differences but some may
        include age, body type, ethnicity, gender, mental ability, physical ability, race, sexual orientation, religion, and social economic
        status (Study.com).
    \n \n <b>Equity: </b>Freedom from favoritism or bias, resulting in justice according to natural law (Merriam-Webster Dictionary).
    \n \n <b>Intersectionality: </b>A way to conceptualize an individual or a group of people that are impacted by more than one type of
        discrimination for example, minority women. Intersectionality takes the overlapping identities and experiences of these individuals
        or groups to understand the  complexities of the prejudices that they must navigate. Intersectionality theory states that that people
        are frequently disadvantaged by more than one source of oppression because of race, ethnicity, gender identity, sexual orientation,
        socio-economic status, and religion to name a few (YWBoston).
    \n \n <b>LGBTQ+: </b>Lesbian, Gay, Bisexual, Transsexual, Queer, Transsexual, Two-Spirit, Questioning, Intersex, Asexual, or Ally.
        Individuals belonging to these groups are also sometimes referred to as belonging to the Queer or Rainbow Community (OK2BME).
    \n \n <b>Marginalization: </b>The process of pushing a person or a group of people to the edge of society by denying them an active
        voice, an identity, or a place within the society. The processes may push the group to the margins directly or indirectly, but
        the result is that marginalized people feel less important and secondary to those holding power and privilege (Syracuse University).
    \n \n <b>Micro-Agression: </b>Intentional or unintentional slights, snubs, or insults that are experienced on a daily basis by individuals
        belonging to marginalized groups. Micro-aggressions can be verbal, non-verbal or even environmental in nature. The messages contained
        in micro-aggressions are often negative, derogatory or even hostile. Many messages are demeaning, and invalidate the experiential reality
        and/or the group identity of the individual. This invalidation sends the message that individuals belonging to this group are lesser
        human beings that have no place within the majority group, leading to marginalization (Psychology Today). It is important to note that
        in and of itself, a micro-aggression is tiny and would not be harmful. Unfortunately though, when micro-aggressions are experienced multiple
        times a day, every day, can have a cumulative effect on the target. These effects can lead to health disparities.
    \n \n <b>The Phobias: </b>Phobias are irrational fears. These fears often lead to discomfort, hatred, or mistrust of individuals belonging to
        these groups. Biphobia, homophobia, and transphobia are not the same thing; straight and gay individuals can be biphobic or transphobic.
        Some people may not be homophobic or biphobic but are transphobic (Planned Parenthood).
    \n \n - <b>Biphobia: </b>The irrational fear of bisexual individuals.
    \n \n - <b>Homophobia: </b>The irrational fear of gay, lesbian, or bisexual people.
    \n \n - <b>Transphobia: </b>The irrational fear of transgender, genderqueer or those who do not conform to gender norms.
    \n \n <b>References: </b>
    \n \n Betancourt, J. R., Green, A. R., Carrillo, J. E., &amp; Owusu Ananeh-Firempong, I. I. (2016). Defining cultural competence: a practical
        framework for addressing racial/ethnic disparities in health and health care. <i>Public health reports.</i>
    \n \n Brown University: https://www.brown.edu/academics/education-alliance/teaching-diverse-learners/strategies-0/culturally-responsive-teaching-0.
        \n \n Hoyt Jr, C. (2012). <i>The pedagogy of the meaning of racism: Reconciling a discordant discourse. Social work, 57(3), 225-234.</i>
    \n \n LiveScience Website: https://www.livescience.com/21478-what-is-culture-definition-of-culture.html
    \n \n Mirriam-Webster Dictionary: https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/equity
    \n \n OK2BME : https://ok2bme.ca/resources/kids-teens/what-does-lgbtq-mean/
    \n \n Penn State University: https://extension.psu.edu/cultural-sensitivity-in-the-workplace
    \n \n Planned Parenthood Website: https://www.plannedparenthood.org/learn/sexual-orientation-gender/sexual-orientation/what-homophobia
    \n \n Study.com: https://study.com/academy/lesson/cultural-diversity-in-the-workplace-definition-trends-examples.html
    \n \n Syracus University: http://counselingcenter.syr.edu/social-justice/impact-of-marginalization.html
    \n \n Psychology Today website: https://www.psychologytoday.com/us/blog/microaggressions-in-everyday-life/201011/microaggressions-more-just-race
    \n \n UC Davis Website: https://psychology.ucdavis.edu/rainbow/html/prej_defn.html
    \n \n UNICEF Website: https://www.unicef.ie/wp-content/themes/iboot-child/micro-sites/itsaboutus/cards/unicef-itsaboutus-gender-sexism.pdf
    \n \n World Health Organization: https://www.who.int/ageing/ageism/en/
    \n \n YW Boston Website: https://www.ywboston.org/2017/03/what-is-intersectionality-and-what-does-it-have-to-do-with-me/</string>
</resources>
